WILLIAMS: Well, Doctor, shall we try again?
怎样, 博士, 我们再试试?
You can suit yourself.
请自便
But I warn you, you're wasting your time.
但我警告你, 你是在浪费自己的时间
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Are you a member of the Draconian Secret Service?
你是不是龙族特勤组的一员?
No.
不是
No change in the rhythm, sir. He must be telling the truth.
没有波动, 他说的应该是实话
How did you get on the cargo ship?
你怎么到货船上去的?
(DOCTOR SIGHING)
I came here in my own ship, the TARDIS.
我是坐着我自己的飞船过去的, TARDIS
- TARDIS? - Yes, my own spaceship.
- TARDIS? - 是的 我的飞船
(MIND PROBE BEEPING)
Why did you help the Draconians attack the cargo ship?
为什么你们要帮助龙族人攻击那艘货船?
DOCTOR: I didn't.
我没有
In any case, it wasn't the Draconians, it was the Ogrons.
而且, 那也不是龙族人, 是 Ogrons
(WILLIAMS SIGHING)
Your machine can't be working properly.
Or else he's controlling it.
你的机器工作不正常, 要不然就是他可以控制它
We've checked all the circuits, sir. Those are his thoughts.
我们都检查过所有线路了, 先生. 这就是他的想法
We know this man is a Draconian agent. He must be lying.
我们知道这个人是一个龙族特工, 他肯定在撒谎
Perhaps he's already been brainwashed, sir.
或许他已经被洗脑了, 先生
But as far as he's concerned, what he's telling us is the truth.
但就他现在而言, 他告诉我们的是实情
Then we must break through his conditioning.
那我们必须攻破他的防线
Unless you tell me the truth, the real truth,
除非你告诉我们实情, 真正的实情
I shall be forced to use increased power.
我只能被迫加大功率了
I wouldn't do that, old man.
我也不愿意这么做, 老头
I know these machines. They aren't awfully reliable, you know?
我了解这些机器, 他们并不是太可靠, 知道不?
You'd do better to worry about the effects on your mind.
你还是操心一下它对你的影响吧
There's just no telling some people, is there, my dear?
有些人就是完全没有判断力, 是吧
Step up the power.
调大功率
Increase to 12.
加大到12
Now!
现在!
(BEEPING INTENSIFIES)
Are you an agent of the Draconians?
你是龙族特工吗?
- DOCTOR: No. - When do they plan to attack us?
- 不是   - 他们打算什么时候开始攻击?
They don't.
他们不会
- How did you board the cargo ship? - Through the TARDIS.
- 你是如何到货船上去的? - 通过 TARDIS
- Who first recruited you to serve the Draconians? - No one.
- 谁招募你服务于龙族人的?   - 没谁
WILLIAMS: Who are the other Draconian agents on Earth?
地球上的龙族特工都还有谁?
I don't know.
我不知道
WILLIAMS: The truth, man. I want the truth.
实情, 我要的实情
- I'm telling you the truth. - WILLIAMS: I will get the truth.
- 我说的就是实情    - 我会得到实情的
(MIND PROBE BEEPING RAPIDLY)
(MIND PROBE SPARKING)
Doctor, are you sure you're all right?
博士, 你确定你没事吗?
Mmm-hmm, apart from a bit of a headache.
当然, 只是有一点头疼
I like the new outfit. Who are you fighting tonight?
我对结果挺满意. 你今晚在跟谁斗?
(JO CHUCKLING)
What happened to you, anyway?
你那边发生了什么?
Oh, they kept going on at me to confess.
哦, 他们一直逼迫我坦白
Yeah, it's awkward, isn't it?
是, 很难堪啊, 对不?
Well, they've made up their minds, you see.
他们自己的想法早就先入为主了, 你看
They'll only believe us if we tell them what they want to hear.
只有我们说他们想听的, 他们才会相信我们
It's a pity really that the Ogrons didn't succeed in kidnapping us.
Ogrons 没能成功绑架我们, 还真是遗憾啊
Perhaps we should have been more helpful.
也许那样我们还能更有用一些
- Why?  - Well, if they had succeeded,
- 为什么 - 这样, 如果他们成功了
presumably they'd have taken us to where the TARDIS is.
应该说来他们会把我们带到 TARDIS 所在之处
(SIGHING) I'm sorry, Jo,
抱歉, Jo
but I'm afraid another kidnapping attempt is our only ray of hope.
不过恐怕再来一次绑架才是我们唯一的希望
So, we just sit around here waiting for
those jolly old Ogrons to turn up again?
所以, 我们就只能干坐在这里, 等着那些搞笑的 Ogrons 出现?
(CHUCKLING) That's about it, yes.
正是如此
The President wants to see you. Get moving.
总统要见你, 走吧
Not you. You.
不是你, 是你
This maybe your chance. Good luck.
这可能是你的机会, 好运
- See you later. - Bye.
- 晚些见   - 拜
(DOOR CLOSING)
I'm giving you a final chance to tell me the truth.
我给你最后一次机会, 你告诉我真相
Madam President,
总统夫人
I've been telling you the truth for some considerable time
我一直在告诉你真相, 颇有一段时间了
but you just won't believe me.
但你就是我相信我
I can't think why you chose to work for the Draconians.
我想不通你为什么选择去为龙族人卖命
But whatever it is, I'll double any offer they've made to you.
不管怎样吧, 他们给你许诺了什么, 我都加倍
That's very generous of you, madam,
夫人, 您真是慷慨
but you'd only be buying information that doesn't exist.
但这是在买不存在的信息
You leave me no alternative.
你让我没有选择了
Under the powers invested in me by the Special Security Act,
根据特别安全法案授权于我的权力
I'm sending you to the Lunar Penal Colony.
我现在发配你去月球刑事殖民地
What, without a trial?
什么, 不进行审判吗?
Without even a chance to state my case?
甚至都不给我一个陈述的机会?
So, you're just tucking me quietly away, are you?
你们就这样把我悄悄地处理了, 是吧?
What about my companion?
我的同伴会怎样?
She will remain here.
她将留在这里
I have hopes that, away from your influence,
我还是有所期待, 远离了你的影响
I might be able to make her see the error of her ways.
我也许能让她看明白她走错了路
But you will see that she comes to no harm?
但你可否盯着点, 让她免受伤害?
We are not barbarians.
我们不是野蛮人
If you want to help her,
如果你想帮她,
why don't you tell me where she comes from?
为什么不告诉我她来自哪里?
I'd like to inform her family.
我好通知她的家人
I'd like to, madam.
我也期望如此, 夫人
I really would, but there's nothing that I can say
that you'd believe.
我真的这样, 但确实我说不出什么你能相信的东西
May I say goodbye to her?
我可以跟她道个别吗?
No! You'll be leaving immediately for the penal colony.
不, 你要立刻出发去刑事殖民地
We're putting you where
your Draconian friends will be unable to reach you.
我们要把你放到你那些龙族朋友够不到你的地方
Penny for them, Miss Grant?
好久不见 (fixme), Grant 小姐?
You! What are you doing here?
你! 你在这里干什么?
To coin a phrase, I've come to take you away from all this.
简单地说, 我来带你远离这一切
What are you talking about?
你这是什么意思
Well, surely you don't want to
spend the rest of your life in here, do you?
你当然不会期望在这里过完你的下半辈子, 是吧?
Well, I'm not going anywhere with you, that's for sure.
这是当然. 但我也不打算同你去任何地方
Oh, but you are, you know.
你会的, 知道吗
Believe it or not,
不管你信不信
I am a fully accredited commissioner from the planet Sirius 4
我现在是天狼星4号的完全授权的专员
and you and the Doctor are two dangerous criminals
而你和博士是两个危险的罪犯
being handed over into my custody.
要转交到我的手中
So it was you!
原来是你!
You ordered those Ogrons to attack the ships
是你命令了那些 Ogrons 来攻击那艘货船
and pretend they were Draconians!
还让他们假装是龙族人!
But, of course!
不过, 当然了
Those lumbering idiots could never have thought up
那些愚蠢的家伙是无论如何也想不出...
such a brilliant scheme by themselves.
...如此天才的计划的
Why did you want to start a war?
你为什么要挑起一场战争?
Now, come on, Miss Grant, be reasonable.
得了, Grant 小姐, 理性一点
You want to see the Doctor again, don't you?
你还想再见到博士的, 对吧?
- Where is he? - He's in another prison, on the Moon.
- 他在哪儿?  - 他现在在另外一个监狱, 月球上
We're going to collect him.
我们要去接他
How do I know you're telling the truth?
我怎么知道你说的是不是实话?
You don't.
你不知道
And the only way you'll find out is by coming with me.
唯一搞明白的方法就是跟我走
Well?
怎样
(SIGHING)
How did you know we were here in the first place?
你怎么知道我们在这里的?
Well, after they'd attacked the cargo ships,
啊, 当那些 Ogrons 攻击了那艘货船之后
the Ogrons returned to their planet, taking their loot with them.
他们带着战利品, 回到自己的星球
Now imagine my surprise, and my delight,
想想一下我的惊讶, 还有喜悦
when I found that they brought me the Doctor's TARDIS.
我发现他们带回来了博士的 TARDIS
And why are you taking us with you?
那你现在为什么要让我们跟你走?
Oh, need you ask?
哦, 这还需要说?
How could I leave two dear friends in such dire straits?
我怎么可能把两个亲爱的朋友留在这么恐怖的地方?
Oh, you don't seriously think that
哦, 你才不是这么想的
I'm going to believe that you want to help us...
我都要相信你是想帮助我们...
Believe what you like, Miss Grant, I have my reasons.
不管你信不信, Grant 小姐, 我有我的理由
Now, are you coming,
现在, 你是跟着走呢?
or do you really wish to vegetate in
this hole for the rest of your natural?
还是打算真在这个洞里耗完下半辈子?
Very well. I'll come.
好吧, 我去
Excellent!
太棒了!
The prisoner and I are ready to leave now, guard.
囚犯和我打算现在离开, 守卫
Anywhere is better than here.
任何地方都比这里好